Guide to the Riki Kobayashi Academic Papers, 1949-1997 UA 323
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Riki Kobayashi Academic Papers
1949-1997
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Kobayashi, Riki
UA 323
2 Linear Feet (2 boxes)
This collections consists of the academic papers of Riki Kobayashi, including his correspondence, publications, and course materials.
Biographical / Historical
Riki Kobayashi was the Louis Calder Chair in Chemical and Biomolecular Engineering. He received his BA in Engineering from Rice in 1944 and an MSE and PhD from the University of Michigan in 1947 and 1951, respectively. His research focused on vapor-liquid phase equilibria, PVT measurement interpretations, hydrate measurement interpretations, chromatographic measurements, transport property measurements, and light scattering in the fluid critical region. His lifelong work benefitted the natural gas industry, and he has close ties to the Gas Processors Association. He also is a member of The Academy of Medicine, Engineering and Science of Texas and the National Academy of Engineering.
Some information taken from--"A Technical Biography of Professor Kobayahi's Work" written by E. Dendy Sloan and Pervaiz Nasir" in the 1980s.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of five series, including academic materials, correspondence, course materials, publications, and student work. Of the five, Kobayashi's publications make up the largest part of the collection.
Conditions Governing Access
This materials is open for research. Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Accruals
Additional materials are not expected for this collection.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials collected and donated by Melissa Kean in 2012.
Index Terms
Subjects
Chemical engineering -- Study and teaching; Chemical engineers -- United States; Chemical engineering -- Research; Universities and colleges
Places
Asian Americans
- Series I: Academic Materials, 1968-1988; 164229
  - A.J. Hartsook Chair of Chemical Engineering, 1968-1972; 164235 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Promotion materials, 1984-1988; 164234 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "Who Will Solve the Technical Problems?", July 12, 1988; 164236 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "A Technical Biography of Professor Kobayashi's Work", ca. 1980s; 164237 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Series II: Correspondence, 1982-1990; 164230
  - Outgoing, 1982-1986; 164238 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Outgoing, 1987-1988; 164239 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Outgoing, 1989-1990; 164240 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Series III: Course Materials, 1953-1980s; 164231
  - Gradebook, 1953-1954; 164241 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Notes and Quizzes, 1970s-1980s; 164242 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Series IV: Publications, 1949-1997; 164232
  - "Methane Hydrate at High Pressure", March 1949; 164243 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - "Gas Hydrate Formation with Brine and Ethanol Solutions", 1951; 164244 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - "Vapor-Liquid Equilibria for Binary Hydrocarbon-Water Systems", February 1953; 164245 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - "Viscosity of Hydrocarbon Gases under Pressure", October 1953; 164246 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - "Metastable Equilibrium in the Dew Point Determination of Natural Gases in the Hydrate Region", August 1955; 164247 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - "Evaluation of Benedict-Webb-Rubin Equation for Prediction of Phase Equilibrium of Light Hydrocarbon Mixtures at Low Temperatures", February 1956; 164248 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - "Evidence of Chromatographic Effect During Flow of Gases Through Oil Field Cores", March 1958; 164249 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - "Low Temperature Vapor-Liquid Equilibrium in Light Hydrocarbon Mixtures: Methane-Ethane-Propane System", January 1959; 164250 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - "Get K-Values by Chromatography", February 1960; 164251 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - "Thermal Conductivity of Light Hydrorrabons and Methane-Propane Mixtures at Low Pressures", July 1960; 164252 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - "Volumetric Properties of Gas Mixtures at Low Temperatures and High Pressures by the Burnett Method: the Hydrogen-Methane System", June 1961; 164253 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - "Application of the Corresponding States Principle to Mixtures of Low Molecular Weight Gases at Low Temperatures and High Pressures", December 1961; 164254 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - "An apparatus for the measurement of the second virial coefficients of vapours; the second virial coefficients of some n-alkalines and of some mixtures of n-alkalines", 1961; 164255 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - "Vapor-Liquid Equilibria at Low Temperatures: The Carbon Monoxide-Methane System", 1961; 164256 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - "Diffusion of Krypton-85 in Dense Gases", February 1962; 164257 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - "High-Pressure Phase-Equilibrium Studies by Gas-Liquid Partition Chromatography", January 1963; 164258 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - "Vapor-Liquid Equilibrium Constants at Infinite Dilution Determined by Gas Chromatography", October 1963; 164259 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - "Volumetric Behavior of Gas Mixtures at Low Temperatures by the Burnett Method: The Helium-Nitrogen System, 0°C to -140°C", 1963; 164260 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - "Hydrates at High Pressure: Part 1", March 1964; 164261 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - "Correlation of the Viscosity of Light Paraffin Hydrocarbons and Their Mixtures in the Liquid and Gaseous Regions", June 1964; 164262 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - "Hydrates at High Pressure: Part II", September 1964; 164263 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - "Determination of Virial Coeffecients by the Burnett Method", October 1964; 164264 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - "Vapor-Liquid Equilibrium Coefficients Determined by Gas-Liquid Partition Chromatography", October 1964; 164265 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - "The Study of Gas-Solid Equilibrium at High Pressures by Gas-Chromatography: Part I", November 1964; 164266 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - "Hydrates at High Pressures: Part III", January 1965; 164267 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - "Thermodynamic Properties of the Helium-Nitrogen System", January 1965; 164268 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - "Generalization of Gas-Liquid Partition Chromatography to Study High Pressure Vapor-Liquid Equilibria of Multicomponent Systems", March 1965; 164269 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - "Compressability Factors of Helium-Nitrogen Mixtures", April 1965; 164270 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - "The Study of Multicomponent Gas-Solid Equilibrium at High Pressures by Gas Chromatography: Part II", July 1965; 164271 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - "The Development of Gas Chromatography as a Method of Determining Vapor-Liquid Equilibrium", 1965; 164272 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - "Development of a High-Pressure Capillary-Tube Viscometer and Its Application to Methane, Propane, and Their Mixtures in the Gaseous and Liquid Regions", July 1966; 164273 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - "Negative Third Virial Coefficients", July 1966; 164274 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - "Calculation of Dissociation Pressures of Gas Hydrates Using the Kihara Model", August 1966; 164275 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - "Prediction of Dissociation Pressures of Mixed Gas Hydrates from Data for Hydrates of Pure Gases with Water", November 1966; 164276 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - "Vapor-Liquid Equilibria of Light Hydrocarbons at Low Temperatures and High Pressures", November 1966; 164277 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - "Hole-Theory Study of the Isochoric Behavior in the Liquid State", April 1967; 164278 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - "Viscosity of Helium and Nitrogen and Their Mixtures at Low Temperatures and Elevated Pressures", April 1967; 164279 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - "Vapor-Liquid Equilibria of Light Hydrocarbons at Low Temperatures and Elevated Pressures in Hydrocarbon Solvents", July 1967; 164280 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - "Physico-Chemical Measurements by Gas Chromatography", October 1967; 164281 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - "Vapor-Liquid Equilibria of the Methane-Methylcyclohexane System at Low Temperatures and High Pressures", October 1967; 164282 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - "Vapor-Liquid Equilibria of the Methane-Toluene System at Low Temperatures and High Pressures", October 1967; 164283 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - "Adsorption Equilibria in the Methane-Propane-Silica Gel System at High Pressures", November 1967; 164284 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - "K-1 Low Temperatures Determination of P-V-T Properties of Gases and Liquids", 1967; 164285 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - "The Measurement of Diffusion Coefficients in Dilute and Moderately Dense Gases by a Chromatographic Technique", 1967; 164286 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - "The Relevance of NGPA Low Temperature K-Value Studies to Low Temperature Hydrocarbon Absorber Design", ca. 1967/1968; 164287 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - "The Correlation of Vapor-Liquid Equilibria of Light Hydrocarbons in Paraffinic and in Aromatic Solvents at Low Temperatures and Elevated Pressures", January 1968; 164288 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - "The Correlation of Vapor-Liquid Equilibria of Methane in Paraffinic, Napthenic, and Aromatic Solvents at Low Temperatures and High Pressures", March 1968; 164448 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - "Virial Coefficients of Methane, Ethane, and Their Mixtures at Low Temperatures", March 1968; 164449 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - "Adsorption Equilibrium of the System Methane-Ethane-Silica at High Pressures and Ambient Temperatures", April 1968; 164450 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - "Applications of the Hypothetical Perfect Gas Perturbation to Study the Continuity Between Gas-Solid and Gas-Solid Equilibrium and to Evaluate Vapor-Liquid Equilibrium", May 1968; 164451 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - "The Hypothetical Perfect Gas Perturbation and the Determination of the Volume of the Adsorbed Phase in Gas-Solid Chromatographic Columns", May 1968; 164452 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - "Theory and Design of an Absolute Viscometer for Low Temperature-High Pressure Applications", June 1968; 164453 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - "Correlations for Adsorption of a Binary Gas Mixture on a Heterogenous Adsorbent--the Methane-Ethane-Silica Gel System", September 1968; 164454 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - "Thermodynamics of Multilayer Adsorption Studied by Elution Gas Chromatography", September 1968; 164455 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - "High Precision, High Pressure Mercury Differential Pressure Manometer", December 1968; 164456 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - "Comparison of the Experimental Phase Behavior of the Methane-N-Heptane, the Methane-Methylcyclohexane and the Methane-Toluene Systems", 1968; 164457 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - "Ethane-Where Do We Go From Here?", January 1969; 164458 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - "Experimental Determination of the Molar Heat and Entropy of Adsorption and the Activity Coefficient of the Adsorbed Phase for the Methane-Ethane-Silica Gel System", March 1969; 164459 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - "An Equation of State for Methane in the Gas and Liquid Phases", November 1969; 164460 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - "Analysis and Recommendations for K-Values for Carbon Dioxide and Hydrogen Sulfide at Infinite Dilution in the Methane-N-Octane System", January 1970; 164289 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - "Low-Temperature Volumetric Properties of Methane", April 1970; 164290 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - "Design needs of low-temperature plant for high ethane recovery", May 1970; 164291 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - "Determination of a Single Set of Unlike Pair Potential Interaction Force Constants from Dilute Gas Thermodynamic and Transport Property Data", May 1970; 164292 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - "Experimental Measurement of Hydrate Numbers for Methane and Ethane and Comparison with Theoretical Values", May 1970; 164293 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - "'Unexpected' vapor-liquid equilibria behavior in the critical region and some theoretical implications of critical exponents", August 1970; 164294 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - "Self-Diffusion Measurements in Methane by Pulsed Nuclear Magnetic Resonance", September 1970; 164322 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - "Circulating Pump for High Pressure and -200 to +400°C Application", October 1970; 164323 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - "Determination of Critical Exponents from Measurements of Binary Vapor-Liquid Equilibrium in the Neighborhood of the Critical Line", November 1970; 164324 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - "Measurements of Gaseous Diffusion Coefficients for Dilute and Moderately Dense Gases by Perturbation Chromatography", 1970; 164325 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - "K-Values at Essentially Infinite Dilution for Carbon Dioxide and Hydrogen Sulfide in the Methane-n-Octane System at Low Temperatures and Elevated Pressures", January 1971; 164326 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - "High-Pressure Adsorption: The Adsorption of Methane on Porasil at Low Temperatures and Elevated Pressures by Gas Chromatography", February 1971; 164327 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - "Data by NMR and Representation of Self-Diffusion Coefficients in Carbon Tetrafluoride and the Determination of Intermolecular Force Constants", September 1971; 164328 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - "Caution! pinch point in Y-X curve!", November 1971; 164329 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - "Vapor-Liquid Equilibrium of Methane-Ethane System at Low Temperatures and High Pressures", January 1972; 164330 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - "Vapor-Liquid Equilibrium of Methane-Ethane-Propane System at Low Temperatures and High Pressures", January 1972; 164331 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - "Vapor-Liquid Equilibrium of Methane-Propane System at Low Temperatures and High Pressures", January 1972; 164332 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - "Direct Steady State Calibration of a Flame Ionization Detector", May 1972; 164333 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - "Micropump--An Apparatus for Steady State Synthesis of Gas Mixtures at Very Dilute Concentrations", September 1972; 164334 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - "Extension to Low Reduced Temperatures of Three-Parameter Corresponding States: Vapor Pressures, Enthalpies and Entropies of Vaporization, and Liquid Fugacity Coefficients", November 1972; 164335 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - "Analysis of Data Obtained by Isochorically Coupled Burnett Experiments", 1972; 164336 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - "F-1 Development of a Method for Direct Determination of Dew Point Loci of Methane-Heavier Hydrocarbon Mixtures at Low Temperatures and Elevated Pressures", 1972; 164338 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - "Thermodynamic Properties of the Adsorbate for High-Pressure Multilayer Adsorption", February 1973; 164340 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - "Vapor Pressure of Normal Paraffins Ethane through n-Decane from Their Triple Points to About 10 Mm Hg", April 1973; 164341 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - "A New Approach to Burnett Cell Design", July 1973; 164342 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - "Virial coefficients of argon, methane, and ethane at low reduced temperatures", July 1973; 164343 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - "Application of BWR Equation to Infinite Dilution K-Values for Carbon Dioxide and Hydrogen Sulfide in Methane-n-Octane System", November 1973; 164366 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - "Dew-Point Loci for Methane-n-Butane Binary System", January 1974; 164367 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - "Unlike Pair Potential Interaction Force Constants for Hydrogen-Light Hydrocarbon Systems", January 1974; 164368 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - "Vapor-Liquid Equilibrium of Methane-n-Butane System at Low Temperatures and High Pressures", January 1974; 164369 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - "Prediction of the Dew Point Locus in Methane-Light Hydrocarbon Binary Systems in the Neighborhood of the Methane Critical Point", March 1974; 164370 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - "High-precision Flow Meter for Gas Chromatography", July 1974; 164371 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - "The Molar Volume and Entropy of Adsorbed Methane on Porasil", August 1974; 164372 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - "Diffusivity of Light Hydrocarbons into Hydrogen", October 1974; 164373 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - "Low Temperature Vapor-Liquid Equilibria of Nitrogen-Ethane System", October 1974; 164374 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - "Low-Temperature Vapor-Liquid Equilibria of Nitrogen-Methane System", October 1974; 164375 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - "Effects of density gradients on measurements of the decay rate of spontaneous density fluctuations in fluids near the critical point", November 1974; 164376 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - "Dew-Point Loci for Methane-n-pentane Binary System", 1974; 164377 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - "Invar Alloy Cell for Isochoric Measurements" (text in Japanese), 1974; 164378 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - "A Reasonable Gibbsian Definition of the Dew Point and its Experimental Verification", January 1975; 164380 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - "Fundamental Thermodynamic and Transport Property Studies Needed for Gas-Processing Technology in Synthetic Oil Production", March 1975; 164381 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - "Dense-Gas Diffusion Coefficients in the Methane-Carbon Tetrafluoride System by Pulsed Nuclear Magnetic Resonance", 1975; 164383 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - "Compressibility Factors for the Hydrogen-Methane System", January 1976; 164384 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - "Vapor-Liquid Equilibrium of Methane-n-Pentane System and Low Temperatures and High Pressures", January 1976; 164385 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - "Dew-Point Loci for Methane-n-Hexane and Methane-n-Heptane Binary Systems", April 1976; 164386 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - "Dew Point Study in the Vapor-Liquid Region of the Methane-Carbon Dioxide System", October 1976; 164387 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - "Experimental Pressure-Volume-Temperature Relations for Saturated and Compressed Fluid Ethane", October 1976; 164393 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - "Viscosity of Methane, Hydrogen, and Four Mixtures of Methane and Hydrogen from -100°C to 0°C at High Pressures", October 1976; 164394 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - "The Interpretation and Correlation of High Pressure Adsorption Data of Methane-Carbon Dioxide Mixtures on 5A and 23X Molecular Sieves", December 1977; 164395 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - "Measurement and Interpretation of the Water Content of a Methane-5.31 Mol% Propane Mixture in the Gaseous State in Equilibrium with Hydrate", January 1982; 164396 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - "Phase Equilibrium Studies for Processing of Gas from CO 2 EOR Projects", June 1983; 164397 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - "Vapor-Liquid-Equilibria Study of Light Gases in Hydrogen-Coal Liquid Model Compound Systems", August 1983; 164398 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - "Hydrate Decomposition Conditions in the System H 2S-Methane-Propane", 1983; 164399 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - "Phase Equilibrium Studies for Processing of Gas from CO 2 EOR Projects (Phase II)", February 1984; 164400 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - "Application of a High Pressure, Multiproperty Apparatus for the Measurement of Thermodynamic and Transport Properties to Measure the Phase and Volumetric Properties of a Supercritical Extractive System: The Carbon Dioxide-N-Hexadecane System", September 1985; 164401 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - "Phase Equilibrium Studies for Process of Gas from CO 2 EOR Projects (Phase III)", February 1986; 164402 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - "Glycol Vaporization Losses in Super-Critical CO 2", June 1986; 164403 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - "The Water Content of CO 2-rich Fluids in Equilibrium with Liquid Water and/or Hydrates", June 1986; 164404 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - "Multi-Component Vapor-Liquid Equilibria Measurements for the Development of an Extractive Distillation Process for the Processing of Gas Issuing from a CO 2/EOR Project", 1986; 164405 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - "To Break an Azeotrope. The Use of n-Pentane To Break the CO 2-Ethane Azeotrope, for CO 2 EOR Gas Processing", 1986; 164406 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - "The Water Content of CO 2 in Equilibrium with Liquid Water and/or Hydrates", July 1987; 164407 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - "Water Content of CO 2 in Equilibrium with Liquid Water and/or Hydrates", December 1987; 164408 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - "Phase Behavior of Supercritically Extractive Systems Showing Three Phase Liquid-Liquid Vapor Equilibria at Lower Temperatures", January 1988; 164409 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - "Vapor-Liquid Equilibrium Studies for the Carbon Dioxide-Methanol System", 1988; 164410 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - "Study at Hydrate Formation/Decomposition Process by a Temperature Ramping Method", July 1989; 164411 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - "Apparatus and Procedure to Measure Binary Total Pressure at High Temperature Fluorene-Phenanthrene Vapor-Liquid Equilibria and Data Reduction by the Four-Suffix Margules Model to Obtain Infinite-Dilution Activity Coefficients", 1989; 164412 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - "A Corresponding-States Correlation of Spin Relaxation in Normal Alkanes", 1989; 164413 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - "Finale Hydrate Stability Conditions of a Methane and Propane Mixture in the Presence of Pure Water and Aqueous Solutions of Methanol and Ethylene Glycol", 1989; 164414 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - "Light Gas Stability in Phenanthrene: The Hydrogen-Phenanthrene and Methane-Phenanthrene Systems", 1990; 164415 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - "Development of an Automated, High Pressure Heat Flux Calorimeter and its Application to Measure the Heat of Dissociation and Hydrate Numbers of Methane Hydrate", 1990; 164416 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - "Solubility of Triethylene Glycol in Supercritical CO 2", 1990; 164417 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - "Spin-Lattice Relaxation and Viscosity in Mixtures of n-Hexane and n-Hexadecane", 1990; 164418 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - "The Water Content of a CO 2-Rich Gas Mixture Containing 5.31 mol % Methane along the Three-Phase and Supercritical Conditions", 1990; 164419 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - "Triple Point Corresponding States in Long-Chain n-Alkalines", 1991; 164420 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - "High pressure nuclear magnetic resonance measurement of spin-lattice relaxation and self-diffusion in carbon dioxide", August 1992; 164421 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - "Interpretation of 13 C NMR of Methane/Propane Hydrates in the Metastable/Nonequilibrium Region", 1993; 164422 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - "Nuclear magnetic resonance measurement of spin-lattice relaxation and self-diffusion in supercritical CO 2-n-hexadecane mixtures", 1993; 164423 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - "Spin-lattice relaxation and self-diffusion near the critical point of carbon dioxide", 1993; 164424 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - "Direct vapor pressure measurement of ten n-alkalines in the C 10-C 28 range", 1994; 164425 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - "Extension of Pitzer CSP models for vapor pressures and heats of vaporization to long-chain hydrocarbons", 1994; 164426 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - "The nature of (p, Vm, T) surfaces of mixtures: (quantum + normal) and (normal + hydrogen-banded), as summarized by their isochoric inflection loci", 1994; 164427 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - "The water content of ethane, propane and their mixtures in equilibrium with liquid water or hydrates", 1994; 164428 (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - "Further Studies in the Elucidation of the Abnormal Solubilities of the Lower Molecular Weight Gases in Aqueous Solutions Near Hydrate Formation Temperatures", 1996; 164429 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - "Solubility measurements for methane and ethane in water, at and near hydrate conditions", 1997; 164430 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - "Rectified Mixed Refrigerant (IGT) Liquefaction Cycle", n.d.; 164431 (Box 2, Folder 79)
- Series V: Student Work, 164233
  General Note
  These materials appear to be the student work of Riki Kobayashi. The exact date of the materials is unknown.
  - ca. 1950s, 164432 (Box 2, Folder 80)